All right, we'll call it over.
The Rager's going to be in my city council for Tuesday, September 3, 2020, 4, we have
both the input and the personal answers.
We do.
There we have the return order of police latch on 21.
Good evening, trustees.
On behalf of the FOP and the President.
We're the large.
I would like to thank you for allowing me to speak on behalf of the FOP, large 121
this afternoon.
Our members, President here today, include trustee, Jason Arnold, Treasurer, Justin Barry, Secretary
Bradley Mullin, Vice President Dustin Hoffer.
We as a large, are here to show support for Chief Thomas Anderson, the logic knowledge
is the need for the city to be transparent and acknowledges and accountable as we are all
held at high standards as representatives for the city and our community.
Chief Anderson loves his department and community.
Chief Anderson has showed this through his dedication, service and sacrifice.
He has made throughout his career almost 30 years.
Thomas Anderson is a proven leader and requires high standards from all his employees within.
Again, thank you on behalf of the locks, 121 for allowing me to speak today.
Thank you.
Three.
Mr.
Five.
Thank you.
All right.
Pardon?
Jones.
Six agreements.
Land plan consultants and corporations for the MIMA Water Park
Capisability Report in the amount of $2,4,980.
The council.
What I bring for you today is step number two in our project, we've been working on for a
couple of years now.
It's with land plan and design professional.
And what this is is a feasibility report.
We're going to do along the project that we present to you guys last year.
We've spent almost $25,000 last year coming up with a concept.
An initial design of a water park feature in the city.
down here, the days are numbered, potentially with a one-floor candidate and we're starting
to look to the future on what we can do to move forward with a pool or water part type
feature. What this feasibility study is going to do is it's going to look at a market analysis
so the demographic which is potential users, facility trends, the demand, so it's going
to review the attendance and forecast usage of the facility that we're looking at. Competition
of the facility, it's going to research the existing aquatic attractions in the area.
One thing we also have to keep in consideration in this area is side analysis, the location
of that proposed water part that we're looking at. The size and layout, have we shot for
the moon? Can we do anything with that? Do we need to shrink it down and make it something
more feasible for what we're looking at? We're zoning and land use, we're both sight
that we're looking at is over here. I'll beat Jay Tunnel where the current splash pad is. We've
talked to DEQ and we're looking at things of what we can do with that site, hopefully this is something
that we can utilize that site for it to expand upon that splash pad complex. Technical feasibility
design, the infrastructure, the engineering, environmental assessments of that area and what
this would do there. Financial feasibility is a big one, the capital cost of this, so timelines
and probable construction costs of this project. Operational assessments, the cost to operate
this pool, make a go with this. Occupensory expectations, is this something that we think that
we can fill on a day-to-day basis? What that would even look like? Economic and social impact.
What could we do with the water part like this? So we've got to look at the impact and the community
possible benefits and risks of having this. We try to do access to the moon and the pressure
way out of it where people can't even come in any way. That's just a few things that this study's
going to give us, the things that we're looking at. The total cost of this whole project for this step
is $24,980 with this in the future, so. And this is something that was budgeted. Thanks.
I'm just going to ask that. I need my dreamer. Most to approve?
I'm seconded.
Hi.
Thank you.
So, I have an annual report from my mobile provider, OK?
Mayor, City Council.
Thank you.
I'm here to share what the city of Miami has been able to provide to the community through
my mobile public library.
So, one of my staff members this morning told me about one of our community members that needed
to apply for a job.
The challenge was, is that you didn't have a smart phone, any type of computer or internet
to apply for that job.
He was able to go to the library, and because of what the city has been able to provide,
he was able to have access to internet, computer, and staff resource to build a apply for
that job.
That's just one of the many stories that creates extra for all of these members.
So, last fiscal year, our budget was less than 40,000.
And we made that into over a million dollar savings for all of our community.
So, imagine every single book, every single resource that someone is checking out how much
would it have cost to them to purchase it themselves.
And this is huge.
That way, they can use it for other things.
So, grants usually grants are not something that you can use on existing, existing things like
staffing or maybe current programming.
This is something that would be new.
And so, even with our budget limitations, grants donations, sponsors have provided a variety
of different types of programming for our community.
Grants do require a significant workload from researching and applying for that grant, continue
to all the way through to the final reporting process.
And so, it does take a lot of our staff members to make that happen, some not so much but some
that it takes every single position to make that happen.
And so, for a program snapshot, you see some of our past programs that we've had, but also
current programs.
And the majority of them have been able to be provided by sponsors, donations, as well as grants.
And this is a huge thing because our programming, but it is limited, but we're so thankful
for our connections and those that are willing to help make that happen.
So, income, the library, we're not made to make revenue.
But we have finally made it to where we're above our pre-COVID year, which is a huge hurrah.
What we're also doing is trying to create a new revenue source.
So, we're actually working on trying to become a facility, a passport facility, so that has already
been approved.
So, we're just waiting on the final pieces to actually make that happen.
So, as soon as we actually have a start date on that, we'll make sure to share it with you.
So, imagination library, you know, we started it back in March of 2023.
We actually have over 800 children enrolled in this program now.
And I'm so thankful for the friends of the library to be able to make this happen.
And so, just to...
minor for everyone.
Magician library is where a child from birth to
after their fifth birthday can actually receive a book
every single month until that fifth birthday.
Four free.
And they just have to work out of accounting.
No limitations.
Next is our Excel high school program.
So that started actually in 2022 as a pilot program.
And then that fall.
We were able to apply for a grant.
We received 10 seats.
And we received funding for technology,
as well as for staffing funds.
So we actually have received approval to use some of our
remaining grant funds for five more seats for ex-high school.
So we have 10 that are actually waiting.
And so we have a very strict application process.
So we're going to be starting that hopefully in the next couple of weeks.
Something else going on that is coming up real soon is our
teen life there.
This is huge.
This helps create support.
We want to support our teen from all.
We also want to help get them connected to the community
as they grow into adults.
We want them to be prepared.
So two of our big pages are our vitals.
So I think of our mural that's in our children's area at the library,
the library being brings the unity and community.
So that's where two of these pages come into place.
So job opportunities.
This is for all of our county.
And where can we actually find a place where we can apply for jobs,
all in one go instead of having to go to each individual
location.
So it's all categorized for different types of service
or different types of jobs that you want to go into.
And we're always updating at almost every single day.
Same with our get connected page.
It's all about groups, volunteer info, assistance programs,
again, the list continues to grow weekly.
And these are two of the resources where, you know,
we're wanting businesses to come into town
and we're wanting people to move in.
These are the two resources I would share
because that way they can see all that we have available for them.
So what's next?
So one, we are working on our outdoor project.
It is finally becoming a reality.
And I am so thankful for street some parks we can do without them.
And all of this is paid for by donations.
So the concrete has finally been poured.
Our book drop, the little platform has already been poured.
So we're waiting on the final pieces of getting our book drop.
Set up and this is not how exactly it's going to look like.
So, but we're also in the process of trying to purchase our furniture.
Just waiting for that a preview.
So it's finally happening.
So just like that individual who applied for that job online,
we have several other examples.
And I could go on.
But I asked my staff this morning like,
why is the library important?
Why is it essential?
Why is it what we do every day?
Why is it important?
So one is accessibility to internet.
Materials and digital resources that are readily available.
Having meetings, spaces, all the programs.
programming that we've been able to bring to the table literacy, we're
cooling and a warming station and we're a place where people can come together
that can connect with others that have common interests and great
connections. So thank you for this opportunity to present. Do you have any
questions? Here's our doing a great job over there, Kayla. Thank you.
Making a series right that our library. Our library team is immediately
I appreciate you guys too. It's no matter what we've told you your way, you guys
always step on it up and get a thing here up. You're not shy to take on
new things and we appreciate it. We're going to just serve.
Great. That's also you.
I'll submit it up dates. It's a library operating machine.
Okay, so I'm just going to share some of the updates.
So one of them is our mission vision and values. So we've had the same
mission for years and it's really about digital inclusion. I'm guessing it's back in the
90's when they decided to make this mission statement. So we're
bringing it up to date to really show the community what we're about.
As well as we didn't have vision or values listed. So we want to be a really
transparent and set ourselves like have a stat like where we need to be and
how we need a perform. Library operating hours is probably one of our biggest
things. So typically Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, we're open from
90 to 8 p.m. It's usually a ghost town after seven.
So there's no reason for us to be open that late. And then for Tuesdays and
Fridays. It also could give us an opportunity to have extended hours. So we're
wanting to go Monday through Friday. The open 90. M to seven p.m. across the
board. It also makes it super easy for individuals to know.
Like, okay, is it the late closing is not the late closing wed day.
Next is we didn't have anything about volunteers. So we added a section and
a similar information and application. Because we really want to
promote that. And then service animals. So we'll just follow the city
policy on the Mima, the service animal policy. And some other things is
so we're going to increase our inner library fee to help cover more of
the cost of from $2 to $3 and then next year we'll probably think about
increasing that again just to inflation of postage. And some of our
fines are changing. So example we're actually changing our threshold to
block library cart privileges from $5 to $10. We've just found that
it would be easier for our patrons. And some of them just have a
struggle paying it all at once. Or I mean there's various reasons why.
But this way they can have access. That's just some of the changes that I could
go on. Any questions?
Thank you. I'd appreciate what you do.
Good night. Show the action on.
to be the man. The hours that's up to us are. We're just writing a lie and to make sure
everybody's aware. We need a boat. We need a boat on the yacht.
I like the boat's for a second.
Hi. Hi.
Hi. The new business of any of which is the business in the space of this agenda.
Ten staff reports. 11 mayor counsel community announcements.
The radio, the radio this year. Well attended on Saturday.
I'd be proud out there. We had a meeting today.
About the bull batch.
Something that gets me a pretty cool deal.
Ronald Mill root 66, right from a comment theater.
The intersections of we transformed into bull riding arena.
And we're going to see how that works.
But so we found that said that I mean, I think I'll cycle out of root 66.
So we're first. So we'll see how we make it work.
Bobby Carter is the best of business.
I kind of stuff. So he, he's ready. I think.
So Derek, he's got to play in.
As well as life and execute and do whatever he needs to do to help.
But so we find that the October 12th at 7 o'clock.
We're going to ride 30 bulls in the middle of Main Street.
30.
Are you doing it?
I'm not.
Do you need to be in the barrel.
Still say we need to take the mayor.
All right. Well, city manager communications.
I don't know anything to say, mayor.
This means I'll say something real fast.
So it's good for me.
I do want to say thank you to the board.
I know you guys, I mean, are not paid to do this.
But, you know, we, we schedule two trips to Salosal and to promocity.
And I appreciate you guys taking time on your schedule together.
I mean, we saw some local things.
These are cities that do fiber and also do a landfill.
So I mean, it was good to see kind of things that they're good at.
And kind of hear what they do and how they do it.
And so I appreciate you guys taking the time under your day to go to that.
Well, I'm going to say something back to you.
We appreciate you having that vision that we have to move money forward.
And fiber is one of those things we've got to have to move money forward.
And man, as much as we're spending on trash, the landfill just makes sense.
So we appreciate you doing that like work.
And get everything set up for us.
We'll go and see a little money.
On your team.
And your team.
So we appreciate everybody rolling the same directions.
Kind of nice.
We appreciate you looking.
Looking forward.
Let's get there.
We lost one pair of sunglasses.
It's pretty much really.
It's better for me.
I think.
There we go.
Let's go.
Okay.
So 13.
and this may be a re-convenient, the Saffron of the first executive section.
Again, they might be a thing.